Finding aid to the Classes of 1971-1980 records CA.MS.01026
Smith College Archives
Classes of 1971-1980 records
1967-2006
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Class of 1971.
CA.MS.01026
7.083 linear feet (25 containers)
Smith College classes have been archiving their historical material by year since 1879. Students who attended Smith in the years covered by these records did so in the context of the Vietnam War and anti-war protests including the shootings of students at Kent State University, the Watergate scandal, an energy crisis and the continuing Second Wave Feminist movement.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Whenever donation information for a particular set of material is known, it is included in the finding aid below. However, a majority of the material was not formally accessioned and its origins are not currently known.
Arrangement
This collection brings together ten record groups that are arranged chronologically, one per graduating class. However, since some materials are placed in a class record group based on when they were created, and not by whom, materials relelvant to a class may exist in more than one series.
Scope and Contents
The Classes of 1971-1980 records consist of individual class notes, examinations, papers and class letters, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, songbooks, class officer records, as well as reunion materials.
Biographical / Historical
Smith College classes have been archiving their historical material by year since 1879. Students who attended Smith in the years covered by these records did so in the context of the Vietnam War and anti-war protests including the shootings of students at Kent State University, the Watergate scandal, an energy crisis and the continuing Second Wave Feminist movement.The Classes of 1971-1980 records consist of 7.083 linear feetr of materials including individual class notes, examinations, papers and class letters, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, songbooks, class officer records, as well as reunion materials.
Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae.; Smith College -- Students.; Smith College. Class of 1972.; Smith College. Class of 1973.; Smith College. Class of 1974; Smith College. Class of 1975.; Smith College. Class of 1976.; Smith College. Class of 1977.; Smith College. Class of 1978.; Smith College. Class of 1979.; Smith College. Class of 1980.; Smith College -- Students.; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae.
- Class of 1971 Records, 1967-2001; 4.167 linear feet (7 containers)
  Biographical / Historical
  The Class of 1971 was the ninety-third graduating class of Smith College.
  Scope and Contents
  The Class of 1971 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1971, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
  - Commencement, 1971 (Box 2248, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1971 (Box 2248, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Carnival, 1967 (Box 2248, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1967-1968 (Box 2248, Folder 4)
  - Groups, 1967-1971 (Box 2248, Folder 5)
  - History, 1967-1971 (Box 2248, Folder 6)
  - Ivy Day, 1971 (Box 2248, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1972-1992 (Box 2248, Folder 8)
  - Reunions, 1976 (Box 2248, Folder 9)
  - Reunions, 1981 (Box 2248, Folder 10)
  - Reunions, 1986 (Box 2248, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 1991 (Box 2248, Folder 12)
  - Reunions, 1991 (Box 2248, Folder 13)
  - Reunions-Directory and Results of Reunion Questionnaire, 1996 (Box 2248, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 2001 (Box 2248, Folder 15)
  - Senior List and Yearbook Index, 1971 (Box 2248, Folder 16)
  - Who's Who, 1967 (Box 2248, Folder 17)
  - Yearbook, 1971 (Box 2248, Folder 18)
  - Individuals A-Z (Box 2249)
  - Pamela Mitchell (Box 2249.1)
  - Caroline Vreeland Rider: A-LN-F (Box 2250)
  - Caroline Vreeland Rider: LN-G-Z (Box 2251)
  - Katherine Gray Rinearson class notes (Box 2252)
  - Margaret Clement scrapbook, 1967-1971 (Box 2252.3)
- Class of 1972 Records, 1967-2004; 1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Class of 1972 was the ninety-fourth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1972 records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1972, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - General, 1967-1972 (Box 2253, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 2253, Folder 5)
  - Groups, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 6)
  - History, 1968-1972 (Box 2253, Folder 7)
  - Ivy Day, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 8)
  - Class Letters, 1973; 2003-2004 (Box 2253, Folder 9)
  - Last Chapel, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 10)
  - Reunions, 1977; 1982 (Box 2253, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 1992; 1997; 2002 (Box 2253, Folder 12)
  - Will, 1972 (Box 2253, Folder 13)
  - Sarah Herbert Gordon research notes (Box 2254)
  - Ann Keck course notes (Box 2255)
- Class of 1973 Records, 1969-2003; 0.625 linear feet (2 containers)
  The Class of 1973 was the ninety-fifth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1973 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1973, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1969-1970 (Box 2257, Folder 4)
  - History, 1969-1972 (Box 2257, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1973-1975; 1996-2003 (Box 2257, Folder 8)
  - Reunion, 1978; 1983 (Box 2257, Folder 9)
  - Who's Who, 1969 (Box 2257, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook Photographs, 1973 (Box 2257, Folder 11)
  - Karen Kaplan yearbook photos (Box 2257.1)
- Class of 1974 Records, 1970-2004; 1.042 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Class of 1974 was the ninety-sixth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1974 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1974, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1974 (Box 2258, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1974 (Box 2258, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1970-1971 (Box 2258, Folder 3)
  - Groups, 1974 (Box 2258, Folder 4)
  - History, 1970 (Box 2258, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1974 (Box 2258, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1974 (Box 2258, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1974-1976 (Box 2258, Folder 8)
  - Reunions, 1979-1984 (Box 2258, Folder 9)
  - Reunions, 1989 (Box 2258, Folder 10)
  - Reunions, 1999 (Box 2258, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 2004 (Box 2258, Folder 12)
  - Who's Who, 1970 (Box 2258, Folder 13)
  - Individuals A-Z (Box 2258.1)
  - Ruth Louise Eliel correspondence from Junior Year Abroad Geneva (Box 2259)
- Class of 1975 Records, 1971-2005; 1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Class of 1975 was the ninety-seventh graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1975 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1975, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - General, 1971-1975 (Box 2260, Folder 1)
  - General-Women's Liberation, 1971 (Box 2260, Folder 2)
  - Commencement, 1975 (Box 2260, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1975 (Box 2260, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1975 (Box 2260, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1971 (Box 2260, Folder 6)
  - Groups, 1971-1975 (Box 2260, Folder 7)
  - Ivy Day, 1975 (Box 2260, Folder 8)
  - Last Chapel, 1975 (Box 2260, Folder 9)
  - Class Letters, 1975-1977; 1984 (Box 2260, Folder 10)
  - Class List, 1974 (Box 2260, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 1980 (Box 2260, Folder 12)
  - Reunions, 1985 (Box 2260, Folder 13)
  - Reunions, 1990 (Box 2260, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 1995 (Box 2260, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 2000 (Box 2260, Folder 16)
  - Reunions-Reunion Book, 2000 (Box 2260, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 2005 (Box 2260, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 2005 (Box 2260, Folder 19)
  - Individuals O-Z (Box 2261)
  - Linda Susan Fidnik questionnaire, class project (Box 2262)
- Class of 1976 Records, 1972-2006; 1.667 linear feet (5 containers)
  The Class of 1976 was the ninety-eighth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1976 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1976, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1976 (Box 2263, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1976 (Box 2263, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1972-1973 (Box 2263, Folder 3)
  - Groups, 1972-1976 (Box 2263, Folder 4)
  - History, 1972-1976 (Box 2263, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1976 (Box 2263, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1976 (Box 2263, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1977; 1985; 2001 (Box 2263, Folder 8)
  - Class List, 1974 (Box 2263, Folder 9)
  - Reunions, 1981 (Box 2263, Folder 10)
  - Reunion, 2006 (Box 2263, Folder 11)
  - Senior Photographs-unidentified (Box 2266, Folder 1)
  - Senior Photographs-A-B (Box 2266, Folder 2)
  - Senior Photographs-C-E (Box 2266, Folder 3)
  - Senior Photographs-F (Box 2266, Folder 4)
  - Senior Photographs-H-K (Box 2266, Folder 5)
  - Senior Photographs-L-M (Box 2266, Folder 6)
  - Senior Photographs-N-Q (Box 2266, Folder 7)
  - Senior Photographs-R-S (Box 2266, Folder 8)
  - Senior Photographs-T-Z (Box 2266, Folder 9)
  - Tenth reunion questionnaire and disassembled scrapbook (Box 2263.1)
  - Records individuals D-G (Box 2264)
  - Records individuals H-Z (Box 2265)
- Class of 1977 Records, 1973-2002; 1.875 linear feet (5 containers)
  The Class of 1977 was the ninety-ninth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1977 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1977, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Records individuals A-B, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1973-1974 (Box 2267, Folder 5)
  - Groups, 1973-1977 (Box 2267, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1997-2002 (Box 2267, Folder 8)
  - Class List, 1974 (Box 2267, Folder 9)
  - Reunion, 1979-1982 (Box 2267, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook Photographs, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 11)
  - Yearbook-Senior Photographs, 1977 (Box 2267, Folder 12)
  - Reunion Book, 2002 (Box 2267.1, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook-Freshman Photographs, 1974 (Box 2267.1, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook-Freshman Photographs, 1974 (Box 2267.1, Folder 3)
  - Individuals C-L (Box 2268)
  - Individuals M-Z (Box 2269)
  - Katherine Louise Falkenberg class notes (Box 2270)
- Class of 1978 Records, 1974-2003; 1.25 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Class of 1978 was the hundredth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1978 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1978, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - General, undated (Box 2271, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1978 (Box 2271, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1978 (Box 2271, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1974-1975 (Box 2271, Folder 4)
  - Groups, 1974-1978 (Box 2271, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1978 (Box 2271, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1978 (Box 2271, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 2003 (Box 2271, Folder 8)
  - Class List, 1974 (Box 2271, Folder 9)
  - Reunion, 1983 (Box 2271, Folder 10)
  - Reunion, 1988 (Box 2271, Folder 11)
  - Reunion, 1998 (Box 2271, Folder 12)
  - Sophomore Push, 1976 (Box 2271, Folder 13)
  - Individuals G-Z (Box 2272)
  - Senior photographs (Box 2273)
- Class of 1979 Records, 1975-1999; 0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
  The Class of 1979 was the one hundredth and one graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class 1979 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1979, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Yearbook Photographs-unidentified, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook Photographs-houses and groups, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook Photographs-art photographs, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook Photographs-A, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook Photographs-B, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 5)
  - Yearbook Photographs-C, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook Photographs-D, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook Photographs-E, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook Photographs-F, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook Photographs-G, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook Photographs-H, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 11)
  - Yearbook Photographs-I-J, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook Photographs-K, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 13)
  - Yearbook Photographs-L, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 14)
  - Yearbook Photographs-M, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 15)
  - Yearbook Photographs-N-O, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 16)
  - Yearbook Photographs-P, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 17)
  - Yearbook Photographs-Q, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 18)
  - Yearbook Photographs-R, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 19)
  - Yearbook Photographs-S, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 20)
  - Yearbook Photographs-T-V, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 21)
  - Yearbook Photographs-W, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 22)
  - Yearbook Photographs-X-Z, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 23)
  - Yearbook Photographs-Staff, 1979 (Box 2274, Folder 24)
  - Commencement, 1979 (Box 2275, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1979 (Box 2275, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1975-1976 (Box 2275, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Reception, 1975 (Box 2275, Folder 4)
  - Groups, 1975-1979 (Box 2275, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1979 (Box 2275, Folder 6)
  - Last Chapel, 1979 (Box 2275, Folder 7)
  - Class Letters, 1998-1999 (Box 2275, Folder 8)
  - Reunions, 1984-1989 (Box 2275, Folder 9)
- Class of 1980 Records, 1976-2000; 1.042 linear feet (3 containers)
  The Class of 1980 was the 102nd graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class Years-1980 records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1980, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Senior Photographs-A, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 1)
  - Senior Photographs-B, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 2)
  - Senior Photographs-C, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 3)
  - Senior Photographs-D, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 4)
  - Senior Photographs-E-F, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 5)
  - Senior Photographs-G, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 6)
  - Senior Photographs-H, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 7)
  - Senior Photographs-I-J, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 8)
  - Senior Photographs-K, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 9)
  - Senior Photographs-L, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 10)
  - Senior Photographs-M, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 11)
  - Senior Photographs-N-O, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 12)
  - Senior Photographs-P, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 13)
  - Senior Photographs-R, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 14)
  - Senior Photographs-S, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 15)
  - Senior Photographs-T-V, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 16)
  - Senior Photographs-W, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 17)
  - Senior Photographs-Y-Z, 1980 (Box 2276, Folder 18)
  - General, 1976 (Box 2277, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1980 (Box 2277, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1980 (Box 2277, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1976-1977 (Box 2277, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Introduction, 1976 (Box 2277, Folder 5)
  - Groups, 1980 (Box 2277, Folder 6)
  - Ivy Day, 1980 (Box 2277, Folder 7)
  - Last Chapel, 1980 (Box 2277, Folder 8)
  - New Faces, 1976 (Box 2277, Folder 9)
  - Questionnaire, undated (Box 2277, Folder 10)
  - Reunion, 1995 (Box 2277, Folder 11)
  - Reunion-Directory, 1995 (Box 2277, Folder 12)
  - Reunion, 2000 (Box 2277, Folder 13)
  - Individuals P-Z (Box 2278)